

KSHITIJ RANGARI

Kshitij.rangari92@gmail.com /C: +1 647 454 4941 Ontario, Canada

SUMMARY

Software Developer, based in Ontario, Canada.

I specialize in web technology, building real world web applications with fantastic user experience. Coming in from multinational enterprise background, I desire to apply my professional and social skills to deliver state of the art software solutions.

SKILLS

Programming Languages:

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- C#

Front End Technologies:

- HTML
- CSS
- SASS

JavaScript Frameworks & Libraries:

- Angular 4+
- Nodejs
- React
- RxJs
- NgRx
- Jest

Web Assembly (WASM):

Blazor

Database Systems:

- Microsoft SQL
- MySQL

Cloud

- Amazon Web Services
- Microsoft Azure

Version Control:

- GitHub
- Bitbucket

Misc. Skills:

- Code review
- Programming development support
- Software debugging
- DevOps processes
- Optimizing and performance tuning
- Project documentation
- Programming and design skills

Tools:

- Microsoft Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- Eclipse
- Postman
- SQL Server Management Studio
- Docker & Kubernetes

SDLC:

- JIRA
- Confluence

EXPERIENCE

Specialist Software Engineer / Larsen & Toubro Infotech Ltd, Canada

05/2021 - Current

Client - Paramount (ViacomCBS), New York, USA

Introduction & Impact -

- Integral part of multiple media asset management applications "The Content Platform" and VMS (Viacom Media Services)
- VMS is a collection of various SPAS (Single page applications) that provides wide range of features such as searching/sorting of content, ingesting new content, video logging capabilities, delivering assets via various workflows, captions/subtitle stitching etc.
- Delivered quality features and products that facilitated best in class media asset management within ViacomCBS.

- Responsible for bringing in innovation to the team by performing POCs and developing working models of new and emerging tech stacks.
- Recognized the importance of having application insights setup within the tech stack which enabled the team to identify crucial metrics and thereby improving the quality of application.
- Played an integral role behind the scenes in making sure "Paramount+" client's feature OTT application was launched within set timeframe.

Technical Duties (75%) -

- Responsible for developing features and functionalities within the stack, with primary expertise in front-end technologies.
- Expertise in working in NgRx with and RxJs with angular.
- Hands on experience in building REST services in C# using DotNet.
- Experienced with writing unit tests with jest on angular and Microsoft fakes on the .net backend.
- Hands on experience with Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio.
- Implemented micro-frontends architecture by introducing UI components built with Angular Elements.
- Experience of working with new non-traditional frontend frameworks like Microsoft Blazor.
- Developed next generation of legacy application with Angular-Typescript, RxJs.
- Hands on experience of working with Docker Containers and Kubernetes.
- Possess understanding of Microservices.
- Hands on experience of working with message broker services like Rabbit MQ.
- Active participation in DevOps processes on Visual Studio Team Services, can efficiently perform Builds, Releases and Deployments.
- Solid experience with Microsoft Azure build and release pipelines can efficiently write DevOps Scripts.
- Solid experience with Version Control with BitBucket, GitHub, can efficiently Commit, Merge, Rebase, Resolve Conflicts and manage branches, which helps in clean software maintenance.

Managerial Duties (25%) -

- Active participation in quarter planning meetings and provide estimations and engineering efforts required to achieve quarter goals.
- Interacting with client on daily basis to understand the critical requirements, following it up with design strategies and implementation.
- Oversee implementation of complex features from front to back.
- Develop strategies and testing plans for new feature requests.
- Perform stakeholder demos making sure that the released features are utilized to its full capacity.
- Perform knowledge transfer and mentor new hires.
- Responsible for preparing technical and self-explanatory documentation for team and users.

Programmer Analyst / Dotcom Team LLC - New York, New York

09/2018 - 05/2021

Client - ViacomCBS, New York, USA

Introduction & Impact -

- Integral part of team VMS Team (Viacom Media Services), an application responsible for managing all the ViacomCBS' media assets.
- Lead development of multiple high stakes feature requests that enabled the client to earn profits.

Technical Duties (75%) -

- Responsible for developing features and functionalities within the stack, with primary expertise in front-end technologies.
- Experience with setting up the project from scratch with a structured approach.
- Solid experience of working with new age JavaScript frameworks like Angular, React, Knockoutjs, jquery.
- Designing complex UI elements using HTML, CSS, and SASS.
- Working with CSS frameworks such as Bootstrap, Angular Material, and Semantic UI.
- Expertise in working with material design.
- Possess deeper understanding of complex angular integrations such as NgRx and RxJs.

- Hands on experience in building REST services in C# using DotNet.
- Basic experience with Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio.
- Coordinating with QA Team for efficient testing leading to high quality feature delivery.
- Active participation in DevOps processes on Visual Studio Team Services, can efficiently perform Builds, Releases and Deployments.
- Solid experience with Version Control with BitBucket, GitHub, can efficiently Commit, Merge, Rebase, Resolve Conflicts and manage branches, which helps in clean software maintenance.
- Providing real time support postproduction deployments.

Managerial Duties (25%) -

- Active participation in quarter planning meetings and provide estimations and engineering efforts required to achieve quarter goals.
- Responsible for preparing flow diagrams and documentations prior to the start of the feature implementation.
- Interacting with client on daily basis to understand the critical requirements, following it up with design strategies and implementation.
- Leading a team of three Full Stack Developers.
- Working in SCRUM Software Process Model.
- Perform code reviews and analysis to ensure high quality coding standards.

Jr. Angular Developer / Insight Global LLC - New York, New York

04/2017 - 09/2018

Client - Viacom, New York, USA

Introduction & Impact -

- Hired as junior developer to build an Ingest tool called as "Bulk Ingest", used by the stake holders to perform bulk ingestion of the content into the system.
- The project used Angular 4 combined with Materialize UI.

Technical Duties (100%) -

- Responsible for developing front end for media applications.
- Experience with various UI design Angular libraries such as Materialize, ngx-bootstrap, Angular animations, etc.
- Gained solid understanding of Various Angular functionalities such as Dependency Injection, Services, Component Communication and Angular elements etc.
- Maintaining cross browser compatibility.
- Fixed Bugs and enhanced UI.
- Interacting with clients and understanding their design requirements.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

New York Institute of Technology

2016

Master of Science: Computer Science

University of Mumbai 2014

Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Engineering

ARTICLES AND PUBLICATIONS

Reusable Blazor Components in Legacy .Net MVC Application - https://medium.com/p/7067ec8c6e7f

CERTIFICATIONS

Amazon Web Services Certified Cloud Practitioner (AWS Fundamentals) – Certificate No (CVZNY2C2Y2EQQ6K3) Amazon Web Services Essentials (AWS) - Lynda.com License No. 4BAA09. HTML, CSS, JavaScript. (Coursera) - License No. XKTAQMBZMQFY.